irr.org.uk 2019-06-17

# Privacy Policy | Institute of Race Relations

#### **Our privacy principles**

WHERE we collect information from an individual, we will never share that individual’s information with a third party, including an advertiser, without that user’s explicit permission. We may publish postal and website addresses of organisations (not individuals) which are already listed elsewhere in the public domain, but we will seek to obtain prior permission where possible.

If you are a subscriber, we will keep your data for so long as you remain a subscriber. If you sent us your name and address in order to purchase a product, we will delete the information within a reasonable period of your receipt of the product and of our receipt of your payment – generally within three months.

For the purpose of data protection legislation, we are data controllers. We use data processors: SAGE for the distribution of _Race & Class_, and Outlandish for the IRR News Bulletins. We have entered into agreements with them to ensure that they process your data in accordance with their obligations under the data protection legislation.

We are fully committed to protecting the privacy of the information we collect. In order to achieve this, we:

  * routinely monitor our electronic security precautions;
  * will only send you emails if you have explicitly asked for them;
  * we will not pass on any individual user details (including your email address) unless we have your prior consent;
  * we may pass on anonymous aggregate statistical information about our users to third parties but these statistics will not include any personally identifying information.

#### **What information do we collect?**

We collect information on our users in two main ways: through subscriptions to our email service and through orders for goods. We only collect that information which we need to provide the services we offer – usually just a name and email address, or a postal address for deliveries.

‘Personalisation’ information entered to customise the news network to a user’s personal interests has the same status as other personal information collected and will not be supplied to any third parties without prior consent. Anonymous aggregate statistical information on ‘personalisation’ may be made available to third parties.

We may also collect anonymous aggregate statistics about our users and traffic patterns, which we use to refine our services. This may be made available to third parties but will not contain any personally identifying information.

The Institute of Race Relations uses all reasonable precautions to ensure that we protect our users’ privacy. We will inform you promptly and in any event within 28 days of any breach of data security. We do not accept responsibility for any actions of third parties which may result.

#### **Cookies**

Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive. At various points we may offer the user the option of storing login or address information in a cookie. Using cookies in this way makes accessing our site more convenient as you don’t need to remember your login details each time. However if you use a shared computer (e.g. in an internet café or college computer room), using cookies can be a security risk as it allows other users access to your personal details.

To avoid this risk, whenever a cookie is about to be stored, you are asked if you share your computer with other users. If you say yes, then no cookie is stored.

Some users express concern about cookies for a second reason, which is that cookies allow websites to track your use of the internet. By collecting this kind of information, websites can identify use patterns and target advertising on the basis of it.

The IRR website does not use information stored in cookies to track your use of our site or match your use of our site with any other website. Cookie information is not shared with any third party. The only use made of cookies by the IRR is to save you having to retype login or delivery address information.

If you are concerned about the security risks of cookies you can select the box which indicates that you are using a shared computer (this prevents all cookies).

#### **Credit card details**

Credit card information is collected through a third party system, provided by [WorldPay](http://www.worldpay.com/). At no point does the IRR hold any user’s credit card details submitted online. Please consult WorldPay for details of their privacy and security arrangements.

#### **Your rights  **

You have the following rights: to be informed about our collection and use of your data; to access your personal data; to correct any inaccuracies in the data we hold on you; to object to any particular use of your data; to have your data deleted wholly or in part; and to be notified of any data breach. Rights of individuals we write about are subject to the exemptions and restrictions set out in the General Data Protection Regulation and the Data Protection Act 2018.
